MICHAEL BENNETT

BASIC INFORMATION

Reinickendorfer Straße 3, 13347, Berlin mbennett156@gmail.com, +491727065406

SKILLS

Forward-thinking team-player with proficiency in multiple general purpose programming languages such as Python and C++, as well as limited experience in many other languages including Dart, Java, JavaScript, R and Groovy.

Have completed several successful projects on ranging from data analysis to designing automation frameworks utilising various industry tools such as Pandas, Jenkins, MySQL, virtualisation and containerisation. Strong knowledge and experience with Linux and Bash. Comfortable using Jira.

- Keen listener
- Happy to take and deliver constructive criticism
- Strong communication skills both verbally and in writing
- Experienced with Agile development
- Experience ranging from solo projects to large team endeavours
- Self-motivated
- Task-oriented

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer

September 2021 - Present

1&1 IONOS

Began work at 1&1 IONOS on 01.09.2021. Here I have been working as a DevOps Engineer as part of the platform compute team.

So far my work has been focused on learning and getting up to speed, with some initial tasks designed to develop the understanding I need to take on more responsibility.

Software Engineer

March 2020 - July 2021

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Spent 6 months playing a leading role in developing a testing automation framework that ties together a mix of third-party (Jenkins, MySQL, Grafana) technologies and in-house tools to streamline performance testing so that it can be easily managed and analysed through graphical user interfaces. This framework orchestrates complex initial configurations and synchronises various forms of data collection to efficiently gather key analysis metrics such as raw performance and bottlenecks across multiple transport layers. Since this successful project, the shift has been towards working in a full software engineering team working on HPE Nimble software, providing regular test-driven deliverables in order to add new features and squash bugs.

Over time have taken on more responsibility such as engaging with and guiding interns, becoming a STEM Ambassador and providing presentations on new technologies in order to share knowledge and experience with various teams.

Systems Engineer

Jul 2017 - March 2020

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

Learned how to manage and maintain HPE servers and storage. Became proficient with Unix terminal access for general and support engineer tasks. Developed a strong understanding of testing preparation and processes. Formed mutually beneficial work relationships to foster a hard-working, collaborative atmosphere. Developed scripting skills for task automation, both for office use and use by customers on the product. Developed programs using Python for data mining and pattern analysis Created highly-detailed spreadsheets with Excel for data-focused trend analysis. Built a reputation as being reliable and helpful, cementing my place as a strong asset to whichever team I was working with at the time.

Bar Staff Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

The Red Lion Pub, Kingly Street, London

Waited on multiple simultaneous customers at the bar, requiring time management skills as well as good communication. Managed bar revenues, ensuring that all customers were correctly charged and all cash accurately accounted for, demonstrating attention to detail and effectiveness under pressure. Cleaned, mopped and vacuumed the bar area, which helped me develop pride for the establishment. Kept track of stock and resupplied the bar in advance to maintain efficiency. Had to work cohesively with a team, including negotiating roles and agreeing on timetables. Maintained full knowledge of beverage lists and prices. Refused service to intoxicated guests to maintain the well-being of the guest and other patrons.

EDUCATION

Computer Science Bsc Sep 2015 - July 2019

Loughborough University

- Upper Second Class Honours.
- Learned and gained an appreciation for a wide range of computer science skills.
- Experienced many modern applications for computer science such as artificial intelligence, or computer vision.

A-level Education Sep 2014 - May 2015

MPW

Achieved ABB, in Mathematics, Economics and English respectively.

ACHIEVEMENT

One of the winners of HPE's Top Talent Intern Programme, an award going to the best interns at HPE for each placement year. Furthermore, out of the 22 winners, I was the only Computing Intern to win the award.

INTERESTS

Servers - I run a home server that runs Proxmox as a bare-metal hypervisor, hosting VMs for home media management and cryptocurrency mining.

Socialising with friends, playing video games, reading, cycling, travelling.